Akitha Medagoda

94A Walmsley road, Favona, Auckland, NZ • 0221631900 • admedagoda@gmail.com https://akitha02.github.io/portfolio/

OBJECTIVE

I'm a 3rd year Mechanical Engineering student with knowledge and experience with numerous engineering projects. I'm trained in principles of mechanical engineering like AutoCAD (Autodesk inventor) and CAE (ANSYS). Highly organized, analytical and detail oriented with excellent communication skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mechanical Assistant

Mar 2022 - June 2022

Cable-Ways -Avondale, AUK

- Mechanical assembler.
- Construct server and battery cabinets from scratch.
- Operate drill press and sheet metal shear machine.
- Operating pneumatic rivet and nutsert gun.
- Maintain utmost discretion when dealing with sensitive topics.

Fabrication Welder

Nov 2021 - Jan 2021

CMP controls. - Mangere, AK

- This role was to help produce electrical Transformers of varies sizes and specifications
- Operating Auto welding machine.
- Manual TIG welding non machinable parts and fixing errors caused by the auto welder.

Volunteer Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

Auckland grammar school - Newmarket, AUK

- Volunteered with groups and organizations to help make measurable differences for program recipients.
- Spoke with community organizations to boost outreach and highlight programs successes.
- Collected donations for causes such as Cystic fibrosis, Auckland city mission.
- Environmental cleanup, mainly around Mount Eden.

Production Worker

Jul 2021 – Jul 2021

Eden Office. - Mangere, AUK

- Supported machine operators in setup and operation of production equipment resulting in efficient runs.
- Conducted performance tests and quality assurance tests of goods to meet product certification requirements.
- Manufactured office furniture using electric and air compressed tools. About 250 chairs per day.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering

2020 - 2023

- Member of Motorsport Club
- Member of Mechanical and Mechatronic student association

The University of Auckland - Auckland city, AUK

Highschool diploma

2015 - 2019

• Member of Cycling squad, Interact club, Cricket, orienteering Auckland Grammar school - Newmarket, AUK

SKILLS

- TIG welding
- Fluent in Autodesk inventor and in ANSYS
- · Web and tech savvy, require little to no training
- · Advanced in MATLAB, C, Python, Html, CSS, JavaScript

INTERESTS

I enjoy improving my programming skills in my leisure time by doing projects like the portfolio website. I love learning and working on automobiles. In the future I would like the improve my welding skill.

REFERENCES

University of Auckland- Senior Lecturer in the Department of Mechanical Engineering

Minas Liarokapis - minas.liarokapis@auckland.ac.nz

Eden Office- Furniture Manufacturer

Michelle - 021 851 439